Hello everyone, good afternoon and welcome to the market for the second of June and look
today it was a fairly uninspiring start to the new week and the new month so we started
the session completely flat and by the end of the day we were down by roughly a quarter
of 1% at 8400 and 14 points but of course this is after wrapping up the second best month
of the year so May was our best month since January we lifted by 3.8% and that helped
to push us into positive territory for the year so far it also got us about 2% away from
the record high that we hit on Valentine's Day.
Now across the different sectors today not many actually rose we only had industrial
consumer staples and telcos ending slightly higher all of the other sectors were down
we saw energy hit the worst despite oil being up about 3% in today's session but as you
can see there energy stocks were down by around 1.4% keeping in mind they were one of the
better performers last week of the course of last week they were the second best performing
sector.
We also saw miners down today as a group but gold stocks within that stood out as a
bright spot as the price of the precious metal rose and financials ended completely flat
by the end of today's session.
In company news Australian investment firm Washington H. Salt Pattinson and also building
products make up brickworks announced plans to merge and create a new listed entity
worth 14 billion Aussie dollars.
The deal will see a newly established ASX listed company Topco acquire all the shares in
Saltpats and also brickworks.
Brinkworks shares up almost 28% to a fresh record high and Saltpats sold by more than 16%
also hitting its highest level ever.
In other news Australia's largest steel maker BlueScope still jumped on the news that
Trump will double tariffs on all steel and aluminum imports into the US from 25% to 50%.
So BlueScope makes roughly half of its profits from its US arm so they could actually benefit
from higher tariffs.
They make about 3 million tons of steel per year in their US operations.
That's about 10 times more than the amount they produce here in Australia and export
to the US.
So this development could potentially provide a further boost to BlueScope's profits in
North America.
And building products company James Hardy told investors they've secured $3.5 billion worth
of credit from 30 participating banks which will support its operations.
And the takeover of US-based building giant ASAC.
On the loses list today, mineral resources and Pilbara were some of the worst performers
after also being near the top of the loses list last week and Lion Town was down a similar
amount today, all partly due to lithium stocks on Wall Street having a tough session on
Friday night.
I also did want to make note of Cancer Treatment Company clarity pharmaceuticals.
They were the worst performance today by quite a margin they were down by almost around
12% actually and at the worst levels of the day they were down by closer to 13.5%.
But interestingly there was no news released on the stock so it could be the case that
they come out with news potentially tonight or in the coming days or maybe the ASX will
send them a bit of a speeding ticket and ask them to explain why it's share price has
moved so much on no news.
So it could be one perhaps to watch in the coming days.
Now over to currency is the Aussie dollars currently buying 64.8 US cents.
It has gotten a little bit firmer in today's session.
Looking ahead to tonight drone power will speak we always have investors listening very
closely whenever a central banker speaks tomorrow on the local front front.
We have the RBA releasing their last minutes from from their meeting where they cut interest
rates by 25 basis points.
We also have agribusiness elders treating ex dividend and tomorrow we will get some manufacturing
data out of China at just before large times so that's one to watch as well.
Have a nice night.