Hello everyone, good afternoon and welcome to the market wrap for the second of June and look today
was a fairly uninspiring start to the new week and the new month. So we started the session
completely flat and by the end of the day we were down by roughly a quarter of 1% at 8,414 points
but of course this is after wrapping up the second best month of the year. So May was our
best month since January, we lifted by 3.8% and that helped to push us into positive territory
for the year so far. It also got us about 2% away from the record high that we hit on Valentine's
Day. Now across the different sectors today not many actually rose, we only had industrials,
consumer staples and telcos ending slightly higher. All of the other sectors were down
we saw energy hit the worst despite oil being up about 3% in today's session but as you can see
their energy stocks were down by around 1.4%. Keep in mind they were one of the better performers
last week over the course of last week they were the second best performing sector. We also saw
miners down today as a group but gold stocks within that stood out as a bright spot as the
price of the precious metal rose and financials ended completely flat by the end of today's
session.
In company news Australian investment firm Washington H. Sol Patenson and also building
products maker Brickworks announced plans to merge and create a new listed entity worth 14
billion Aussie dollars. The deal will see a newly established ASX listed company Topco acquire all
the shares in Solpats and also Brickworks. They said Brickworks shares up almost 28% to a fresh
record high and Solpats soared by more than 16% also hitting 3%.
In other news Australia's largest steel maker Blue Scope Steel jumped on the news that Trump
will double tariffs on all steel and aluminium imports into the US from 25% to 50%. So Blue Scope
makes roughly half of its profits from its US arm so they could actually benefit from higher tariffs
they make about 3 million tons of steel per year in their US operations that's about 10 times more
than the amount they produce here in Australia and extra money for the US. So that's a lot of
export to the US. So this development could potentially provide a further boost to Blue
Scope's profits in North America and building products company James Hardy told investors
they've secured three and a half billion dollars worth of credit from 30 participating banks which
will support its operations and the takeover of US based building giant ASX. On the losers list
today Mineral Resources and Pilbara were some of the worst performers after also being near the top
of the losers list. So the losers list today Mineral Resources and Pilbara were some of the
worst performers after also being near the top of the losers list. So the losers list last week and
Lyontown was down a similar amount today all partly due to lithium stocks on Wall Street
having a tough session on Friday night. I also did want to make note of cancer treatment company
Clarity Pharmaceuticals. They were the worst performer today by quite a margin. They were down
by almost around 12% actually and at the worst levels of the day they were down by closer to
thirteen and a half percent. But interestingly there was no news released on the stocks so
it could be the case that they come out with news potentially
potentially tonight or in the coming days or maybe the ASX will send them a bit of a speeding
ticket and ask them to explain why its share price has moved so much on no news so it could be one
perhaps to watch in the coming days now over to currencies the Aussie dollar is currently buying
64.8 US cents it has gotten a little bit firmer in today's session looking ahead to tonight Jerome
Powell will speak we always have investors listening very closely whenever a central banker
speaks tomorrow on the local front we have the RBA releasing their last minutes from from their
meeting where they cut interest rates by 25 basis points we also have agribusiness elders
trading ex-dividend and tomorrow we will get some manufacturing data out of China
at just before lunchtime so that's one to watch as well have a nice night
you