Hello everyone, good afternoon and welcome to the market wrap for the 2nd of June and
look today was a fairly uninspiring start to the new week and the new month.
So we started the session completely flat and by the end of the day we were down by
roughly a quarter of 1% at 8,414 points but of course this is after wrapping up the second
best month of the year.
So May was our best month since January, we lifted by 3.8% and that helped to push us
into positive territory for the year so far, it also got us about 2% away from the record
high that we hit on Valentine's Day.
Now across the different sectors today not many actually rose, we only had industrials,
consumer staples and telcos ending slightly higher.
All of the other sectors were down, we saw energy hit the worst despite oil being up
about 3% in today's session but as you can see there energy stocks were down by around
1.4%.
Keep in mind they were one of the better performers last week, over the course of last
week they were the second best performing sector.
We also saw miners down today as a group but gold stocks within that stood out as a bright
spot as the price of the precious metal rose and financials ended completely flat by the
end of today's session.
In company news, Australian investment firm Washington H. Solpatinson and also building
products maker Brickworks announced plans to merge and create a new listed entity worth
AU$14 billion.
The deal will see a newly established ASX listed company Topco acquire all the shares
in Solpats and also Brickworks.
This sent Brickworks shares up almost 28% to a fresh record high and Solpats sawed by
more than 16% also hitting its highest level ever.
In other news, Australia's largest steel maker Blue Scope Steel jumped on the news that Trump
will double tariffs on all steel and aluminium imports into the US from 25% to 50% so Blue
Scope makes roughly half of its profits from its US arm so they could actually benefit
from higher tariffs, they make about 3 million tonnes of steel per year in their US operations
that's about 10 times more than the amount they produce here in Australia and export
to the US.
So this development could potentially provide a further boost to Blue Scope's profits in
North America.
And building products company James Hardy told investors they've secured $3.5 billion
worth of credit from 30 participating banks which will support its operations and the
takeover of US-based building giant ASIC.
On the losers list today, Mineral Resources and Pilbara were some of the worst performers
after also being near the top of the losers list last week and Liontown was down a similar
amount today all partly due to lithium stocks on Wall Street having a tough session on Friday
night.
I also did want to make note of cancer treatment company Clarity Pharmaceuticals, they were
the worst performer today by quite a margin, they were down by almost around 12% actually
and at the worst levels of the day they were down by closer to 13.5% but interestingly
there was no news released on the stock so it could be the case that they come out with
news potentially tonight or in the coming days or maybe the ASX will send them a bit
of a speeding ticket and ask them to explain why its share price has moved so much on no
news.
So it could be one perhaps to watch in the coming days.
Now over to currencies, the Aussie dollar is currently buying 64.8 US cents, it has
gotten a little bit firmer in today's session.
Looking ahead to tonight Jerome Powell will speak, we always have investors listening
very closely whenever a central banker speaks.
Tomorrow on the local front we have the RBA releasing their last minutes from their meeting
where they cut interest rates by 25 basis points.
We also have agribusiness elders trading ex-dividend and tomorrow we will get some manufacturing
data out of China at just before lunchtime so that's one to watch as well.
Have a nice night.