Hello, I'm Ron Good afternoon and welcome to the market wrap for the second of June and
look today. It was a fairly uninspiring start to the new week and the new month. So we started
the session completely flat and by the end of the day we were down by roughly a quarter of
1% at 8,400 and 14 points but of course this is after wrapping up the second best month of
the year. So May was our best month since January we lifted by 3.8% and that helped push us into
positive territory for the year so far. Also got us about 2% away from the record high that we hit
on Valentine's Day. Now across the different sectors today not many actually rose. We only had
industrial consumer staples and telcos ending a slightly higher. All of the other sectors were
down we saw energy hit the worst despite oil being up about 3% in today's session but as you can see
there energy stocks were down by around 1.4%. Keep in mind they were one of the better performers
last week of the course of last week they were the second best performing sector. We also saw
miners down today as a group but gold stocks within that stood out as a bright spot as the price
of the precious metal rose and financials ended it completely flat by the end of today's session.
In company news Australian investment firm Washington H. Sol Patinson and also building products
make up brickworks announced plans to merge and create a new listed entity worth 14 billion
Aussie dollars. The deal will see a newly established A6 listed company Toko acquire all the shares
in solpats and also brickworks. This set brickwork shares up almost 28% to a fresh record high
and solpats sold by more than 16% also hitting its highest level ever. In other news Australia's
largest steel maker BlueScope still jumped on the news that Trump will double tariffs on all
steel and aluminium imports into the U.S. from 25% to 50%. BlueScope makes roughly half of its profits
from its U.S. arm so they could actually benefit from higher tariffs that they make about 3 million
tons of steel per year in their U.S. operations. That's about 10 times more than the amount they
produce here in Australia and export to the U.S. So this development could potentially provide a
further boost to BlueScope's profits in North America and building products company James Hardy
told investors they've secured $3.5 billion worth of credit from 30 participating banks which will
support its operations and the takeover of U.S. based building giant Hazac. On the loses,
list today, mineral resources and silver are worth some of the worst performers after also being
near the top of the loses list last week and Lion Town was down a similar amount today or partly
due to Lithium stocks on Wall Street having a tough session on Friday night. I also did want to
make note of cancer treatment company Clarity Pharmaceuticals. They were the worst performance today
by quite a margin they were down by almost around 12 percent actually and at the worst levels of
the day they were down by closer to 13.5 percent but interestingly there was no news released on
the stock so it could be the case that they come out with news potentially tonight or in the
coming days or maybe the ASX will send them a bit of a speeding ticket and ask them to explain why
chair price has moved so much on no news. So it could be one perhaps to watch in the coming days.
Now over to currencies the Aussie dollar is currently buying 64.8 US cents it has got
on a little bit firmer in today's session. Looking ahead to tonight drone power will speak.
We always have investors listening very closely whenever a central bank at speaks.
Tomorrow on the local farm front we have the RBA releasing their last minutes from the meeting
where they can't interest rates by 25 basis points. We also have Agree Business Elders
trading ex dividend in tomorrow we will get some manufacturing data out of China just before
launch time so that's one to watch as well have a nice night.