Hello everyone, good afternoon and welcome to the market wrap for the second of June
and look today was a fairly uninspiring start to the new week and the new month.
So we started the session completely flat and by the end of the day we were down by
roughly a quarter of one percent at eight thousand four hundred and fourteen points.
But of course this is after wrapping up the second best month of the year.
So May was our best month since January.
We lifted by three point eight percent and that helped to push us into positive territory
for the year.
So far it also got us about two percent away from the record high that we hit on Valentine's
Day.
Now across the different sectors today not many actually rose.
We only had industrials, consumer staples and telcos ending slightly higher.
All of the other sectors were down.
We saw energy hit the worst despite oil being up about three percent in today's session.
But as you can see their energy stocks were down by around one point four percent.
Keep in mind they were one of the better performers last week over the course of last week.
They were the second best performing sector.
We also saw miners down today as a group but gold stocks within that stood out as a bright
spot as the price of the precious metal rose and financials ended completely flat by the
end of today's session.
In company news, Australian investment firm Washington H. Sol Pattinson and also building
products make up Brickworks announced plans to merge and create a new listed entity worth
14 billion Aussie dollars.
The deal will see a newly established ASX listed company Topco acquire all the shares
in Solpats and also Brickworks.
They sent Brickworks shares up almost twenty eight percent to a fresh record high and Solpats
by more than 16 percent also hitting its highest level ever.
In other news, Australia's largest steel maker Blue Scope Steel jumped on the news that
Trump will double tariffs on all steel and aluminium imports into the US from 25 percent
to 50 percent.
So Blue Scope makes roughly half of its profits from its US arm so they could actually benefit
from higher tariffs.
They make about three million tons of steel per year in their US operations.
That's about ten times more than the amount they produce here in Australia and export
to the US.
So this development could potentially provide a further boost to Blue Scope's profits
in North America.
And building products company James Hardy told investors they've secured three and a
half billion dollars worth of credit from 30 participating banks which will support its
operations and the takeover of US based building giant ASEC.
On the losers list today mineral resources and Pilbara were some of the worst performers
after also being near the top of the losers list last week and Lyontown was down a similar
amount today all partly due to Lithium stocks on Wall Street having a tough session on Friday
night.
I also did want to make note of cancer treatment company Clarity Pharmaceuticals.
They were the worst performer today by quite a margin.
They were down by almost around 12 percent actually and at the worst levels of the day
they were down by closer to 13 and a half percent.
But interestingly there was no news released on the stock so it could be the case that
they come out with news potentially tonight or in the coming days or maybe the ASX will
send them a bit of a speeding ticket and ask them to explain why its share price has moved
so much on no news.
So it could be one perhaps to watch in the coming days.
Now over to currencies the Aussie dollar is currently buying 64.8 US cents.
It has gotten a little bit firmer in today's session.
Moving ahead to tonight drone power will speak.
We always have investors listening very closely whenever a central banker speaks.
Tomorrow on the local front we have the RBA releasing their last minutes from their meeting
where they cut interest rates by 25 basis points.
We also have agribusiness elders trading ex-dividend and tomorrow we will get some manufacturing
data out of China at just before lunchtime so that's one to watch as well.
Have a nice night.